In the end,
到最后
those who are deceived will continue to be deceived.
被骗的人就是会一直被骗
Those without power can't obtain information.
无权无势的人就得不到情报
They have no knowledge, so they continue to lose.
不知道情报 就会继续输下去
Have you heard of Swimmy?
你听说过《小黑鱼》吗？
That story of a group of weak small fishes gathering together.
一大群弱小的鱼团结起来的故事
Are the weak small fishes still weak even if tons of them gather together?
弱小的鱼 即使大量聚集还是很弱吗？
The picture book?
绘本？
That's right.
没错
The picture book.
绘本
Wataro, you say the funniest things.
棉郎先生 你说话真有趣
Do I?
是吗？
Even if they form a group,
即使形成集团
weak people will always be weak.
弱小的人还是很弱小吧
I guess so.
也是
It won't be like a picture book, huh?
绘本跟现实是两回事吗？
Talking about fish made me want to eat one.
说起鱼我就好想吃鱼
I'm craving rosy seabass.
好想吃赤鯥啊
"I'll be gone for a few days."
“我要出门几天”
He won't reply to my messages.
问他也不回我信息
Even though he has Mr. Takaoka's case to work on.
他手上明明还有高冈先生的案子
We are investigating the other person mentioned in the testimony.
我们正在调查证词里提到的 当时也在场的另一个人
But the security camera in the area only captured
附近的监视器在犯案时间前后
about ten people walking by before and after the incident.
拍到大约10个人经过现场
And we haven't identified anyone other than Mr. Taku Oba.
除了大庭拓先生以外 无法确定其他人的身份
The only thing left at the crime scene were two charred oil lighters.
现场残留的 只有两个烧焦的灌油式打火机
This matches our eyewitness, Mr. Taku Oba's testimony
根据目击者大庭拓先生表示
that Mr. Hyuga tried to set himself on fire but didn't succeed.
死者日向先生想要点火自焚却点不着
And right after that, someone dropped a blue lighter into the gasoline.
后来有个人把蓝色打火机丢到汽油上 现场物证和目击证词是一致的
Several footprints have been found on the scene,
现场发现了几个人的鞋印
which we're rushing to identify.
我们正加紧确认
We're also looking at the alibis
我们也在确认和日向先生有关的人
of people connected to Mr. Hyuga, but we have nothing useful yet.
是否有不在场证明 目前尚未得到有力情报
I'm terribly sorry.
真的很抱歉
My misunderstanding caused you and your brother trouble.
因为我的误解 让大庭先生和你弟弟陷入了麻烦
It's fine. My brother's innocence was proven
别这么说 因为日向太太提供的证词
thanks to your testimony.
才能证明我弟弟的清白
Due to the position we're in, we can't exactly tell you to sue them.
以我们的立场 不太适合建议您提告
So, I will.
那就由我来建议吧
How about you sue Green Estate?
要不要对绿色不动产提告？
I'm responsible for lending my name too.
我出借名字也有责任
I'll support you during the trial.
在诉讼期间会全力支持您的
Well, but…
但是…
He's already quit the company and resigned from the president position.
他已经离职 也辞去社长职位了
That's right. I'm unemployed.
对 我失业了
We will prove that it's fraud and get your money back.
我们会证明这是诈骗 帮你们把损失金额要回来
What do you think?
您意下如何？
Let's speak up together.
我们一起发声吧
I'd like to sue them.
拜托你们了
Okay.
好
President Tone, I'd like to speak with you.
刀根社长 有话要跟你说
This is Mr. Haneoka, a lawyer--
这位是羽根冈律师…
I have nothing to say to a lawyer.
我跟律师没什么好说的
You tricked me.
你骗了我
You've already quit. What is it?
你都辞职了 还跑来做什么？
My brother got caught up in this because of me.
这次因为我 害我弟弟也牵连其中
I won't let this slide. I'll cooperate with the fraud victims too.
我绝不会这么放过你 我也会协助诈骗的受害者
On what basis are you calling it fraud?
说我诈骗 你有什么根据吗？
I'll sue you, asshole.
小心我告你 混蛋
Let's fight this together.
我们一起奋战吧
How about suing them together?
你们要不要联合提告呢？
You're both victims of fraud by different companies.
日向太太和高冈先生 是受到不同公司的诈骗
But there are many similarities.
但是物件特征和诈骗手法
Such as the property's characteristics, their method
还有装修业者都是相同的
and they used the same renovation contractor.
两个案子有非常多的共同点
From that, we think it might be an integral fraud by the same group.
因此我们怀疑这可能是 同一集团的诈骗行为
If we could proceed with this as one lawsuit,
我们会去厘清这两家公司的关连性
while clarifying the connection of these two companies, we could--
以同一起诉讼案件来处理 这样会比较容易搜集到证据…
If they'll compensate me earlier that way, then please.
如果这样能早点拿到赔偿的话 那就拜托了
If this goes on any longer,
再这样拖下去
I'll have to sell my clinic and live out on the street.
我只能卖掉整复院 流落街头了
I'm in too.
拜托你们了
Okay.
好
Then, we'll proceed with the preparations.
那么接下来我们就会开始准备
By the way…
顺便问一下…
Mr. Takaoka, do you know this man?
高冈先生 你认识这个人吗？
He was the president of Green Estate when Mr. Hyuga was deceived.
他是日向先生遭到诈骗时的 绿色不动产社长
No, I don't know him.
不 我不认识
I see.
这样啊
We might be jumping the gun, but should we just file the lawsuit?
虽然有点仓促 但要不要先提出诉状再说
No! We don't have enough evidence to prove that those two are connected.
不可以 这两个案子有关联的证据 还太薄弱
Yeah. You haven't stopped me like that in a while.
也是 好久没听到 你说“不可以”了
Alright!
好
What's wrong?
怎么了？
What's up?
发生了什么事？
Huh? Oh, I'm just happy I get to be a part of this atmosphere.
能再次参与两位的这种气氛 我感到很开心
"This atmosphere"?
“这种气氛”？
Yes.
对
Your positions are different but you're equal.
虽然立场不同 但彼此对等的气氛
I've never seen that in a workplace before.
我在职场上从来没有见过这样的气氛
I'll make sure to get into such a company next time.
下次我一定要找到这样的职场
Alright! Do your best.
很好 加油
I will!
好
But you have bad luck with companies.
但你的工作运真的很差
Yeah, really. That's the problem.
真的 那就是问题所在
-I'm home. -Why…
-我回来了 -为什么…
Dad! Where have you been?
爸 你跑去哪里了？
I was investigating.
我去调查案子啊
For the fraud?
诈骗案吗？
Yeah, can I sit first?
对 先让我坐下来
I'll tell you everything.
再慢慢说给你们听
Is it your back?
是腰在痛吗？
No, it's my lower hip this time.
不是腰 这次是坐骨
Let me confirm.
让我确认一下
For the past six months,
爸爸在这过去半年来
you've been going to the bar owned by Yotsuboshi Housing's President Sakakibara
经常出入 四星房屋的榊原社长经营的酒吧
for information and became a regular, while hiding your identity.
为了搜集情报 隐瞒身份 成为了常客
That's right.
没错…
The other day, the bartender told you that
前几天去店里时 听酒保说
President Sakakibara often went to Ishikawa and Toyama
榊原社长在去年常常到石川县
for business trips last year.
和富山县出差
In hopes of finding evidence of him purchasing old properties at low prices
为了找到他以低价收购旧屋的证据
and anything that could lead to fraud, you went to those locations.
以及任何跟诈骗案有关的线索 就到当地去调查了
That's right.
对
I bought their local specialty, rosy seabass.
这是当地带回来的伴手礼 赤鯥
And they said this is good. It's oil blotting paper.
还有这个好像也不错 是吸油面纸…
You should've just told us.
这样的话 就要说啊
Well, I knew it wouldn't be easy to gather evidence.
因为要找到证据 但又没那么简单
And I thought you'd nag me and tell me not to take the bullet train and--
这样的话 硝子又会说 不要搭新干线…
I wouldn't say that.
我才不会这么说
Really? You wouldn't tell me to take the overnight bus instead?
真的吗？ 不会叫我搭夜间巴士就好吗？
-She definitely would. -I wouldn't.
-她会这么说 -才不会
And did you find something?
您查到什么了吗？
Well, you know. It's not that easy to--
就说了 没那么简单嘛…
Wasted expense.
钱都白花了
Oh, by the way, have you heard of Mr. Mikogami?
对了 你们知道御子神先生吗？
-The investor. -Yes.
-那个投资人吗？ -对
You know, Mr. Mikogami is a regular at Mr. Sakakibara's bar.
御子神先生是榊原先生酒吧的常客
So, I got to meet him and he gave me advice on things.
我后来也认识他了 偶尔会听他发表高见
And I saw his photo in Ishikawa.
我在石川县的照片里看到他
Could you take a look? This is Mr. Sakakibara, right?
你们看 这位是榊原先生吧？
And this guy. The one in the mirror.
然后这边 在镜子里
If I zoom in, see?
我把它放大 你们看
-Oh. -You're right.
-哦 -还真是
-That's Mr. Mikogami, right? -Oh!
-这个人是御子神先生吧？ -哦
This one is President Tone.
这是刀根社长
What?
什么？
I'm sure. With the vest and everything.
这个感觉一定是他 穿着背心的感觉
We got him!
出现了
Tone and Sakakibara are connected!
刀根和榊原果然有关连
What does Mr. Mikogami have to do with this?
御子神先生跟本案有什么关系？
We'll figure that out after we file the lawsuit. Okay?
等提出诉状之后再来调查 好吗？
Good job, me.
我真是好样的
A job well done!
立了大功
It's an indisputable fact that carbon neutrality must be implemented
碳中和是我们面对气候变迁
as a weather change measure.
必然要实施的对策 这点毋庸置疑
However!
然而
Most people think that our country and big companies will do it for us.
大多数人认为 国家和大企业会为我们做这件事
Through policymaking,
通过制定政策
we need to change the mindset of people and society.
我们必须改变民众和社会的心态
AO
（苍）
I filed the lawsuit.
我提起诉讼了
Good job. Thanks.
好样的 谢谢
But the more we look into it, the more complex this fraud gets.
不过这个诈骗案真的是愈查愈不妙
Yeah, they're skillfully using the loopholes in the law.
非常巧妙地钻过了法律漏洞
I didn't know it was so clever.
他们的手法有那么巧妙吗？
Oba.
大庭
Yes.
是
Say you have more than enough savings and you decide to buy an apartment.
假设你有一笔不小的存款 想要买一栋公寓
Okay.
是
You'd want to take a look at the rooms, right?
你会想去看公寓的屋况吧？
Of course.
当然
So, you go and see it
你去看了
and you found a fully renovated, clean and stylish room.
那是一间全面翻新 漂亮又时髦
The room of your dreams.
超级理想的房间
You can't see the other rooms because it's currently occupied,
其他房间因为现在都有人住 没办法让你进去看
but of course they've been renovated too.
当然 所有的房间都经过修缮
And if they say it's very popular, so you need to sign the contract now
这栋公寓现在非常抢手 不赶快签约就买不到
or you won't be able to buy it…
对方跟你说 要买就要趁现在
-I'll buy it. -Wrong! Bad decision.
-我要买 -不行 出局
-Why? -Bad decision.
-为什么？ -出局了
Changing just one tatami mat can be considered a renovation.
即使只换一张榻榻米也能算是修缮
What?
什么？
You mean other than the nice room I saw,
你是说除了我看过的漂亮房间以外
others only had one tatami mat changed and are in shambles?
其他都是只换了一张榻榻米 破破烂烂的房间吗？
-Yes. -That's fraud.
-对 -这是诈骗吧
But the police would blame you for not checking and they won't do anything.
但警方会说你没有先进去确认 也有不对 所以不会采取行动
That's not fair.
怎能这样
There will always be cunning crooks who exploit people.
不管什么时代都有这种 利用狡猾手段剥削他人的家伙
I wonder if the contractor in Ishikawa
负责翻修这两栋房子的
that renovated those two properties is in on it.
石川县的施工业者也是同伙吧
That's the thing.
重点就在这里
I doubt Green Estate nor Yotsuboshi would do something risky like that.
我怀疑绿色不动产 或四星房屋会露出马脚
If we were to attack, it's that contractor.
如果要找突破口 只能从施工业者下手了
But they're not picking up.
但是完全联络不到对方
I see.
这样啊
AYA HYUGA
（日向绫）
Hello.
你好
I'm thinking of withdrawing the lawsuit.
我在犹豫要不要撤诉
Why is that?
这是为什么？
I've been getting harassing phone calls from strangers.
有陌生人打电话骚扰我
Saying, "It's your fault for investing," and "You brought this on yourself."
说“谁叫你们要投资” “自作自受”
When people ask me if I'm not ashamed of making a scene,
“在网络上被骂成那样 不觉得丢脸吗？”
I think that maybe I should be.
听到这些话 我觉得好像也没错
Ma'am, you should continue this trial.
太太 这场官司应该要继续打下去
You didn't make a bad investment.
你们不是投资失败
You were deceived.
而是被骗了
Excuse me.
不好意思
We'll investigate the harassment right away.
那些骚扰电话 我们会立刻去查
But…
可是…
Um…
嗯…
Those people who are irresponsibly criticizing you will not save you.
那些不负责任批评你的人不会救你
Please protect yourself by speaking up.
请你主动发声 保护自己
That way, we can be there for you.
这样的话 我们也会和你站在一起
Right.
好
I'm sorry for being weak.
对不起 变得这么软弱
It's fine.
不会
Okay.
再见
Despite the way I look, I also get weak--
别看我这样 我也常常会变得软弱…
S-She hung up.
她…挂电话了
So, it's this.
是这个吗？
SENOO ARSON MURDER BEREAVED FAMILY FACES CRITICISM
（妹尾市纵火杀人案 批评遗族的声浪不断）
Oh, that might be our opponent's doing.
那个说不定是对手在煽风点火
What?
什么？
There's a lawyer named Inuzuka on the defendant's team.
被告的律师团里有个叫犬冢的
He's the boss of a big firm.
他是大型事务所的老板
He's the type who would do anything to win.
这个人为了胜诉会不择手段
He should quit already.
他应该早点辞职算了
I hope she gets her smile back.
希望她能重拾笑容
Like it said in Mr. Hyuga's letter.
像日向先生信里写的那样
Yeah.
是
Oh, there you are. The next meeting is at the Prime Minister's office.
找到您了 下一场会议是在首相官邸
The Deputy Minister will be there too.
副大臣也会参加
Okay.
知道了
No. This is bad. So bad.
不 这下糟了
I don't feel like we can win at all.
再这样下去 根本赢不了
We can hear you.
你的心声都跑出来了
But if we postpone the trial, Mr. Takaoka will be in trouble.
但官司再拖下去的话 高冈先生就惨了
Right. We have to do something by tomorrow.
没错 明天一定要想点办法
Tomorrow? Come on--
明天？真是…
Let's calm down.
先冷静一下吧
Inhale.
吸气
Haneo. One more time.
羽男先生 再一次
Yeah?
喂？
Huh? Oh, uh…
嗯？啊…
Who is this? Stop calling.
谁啊？烦不烦啊？
-Hello! Is this Mr. Akiyama-- -Ouch! Ow…
-喂 秋山先生吗… -好痛…
TRIAL DAY
（开庭日）
So, you do own a suit.
您也有这么正式的西装啊
Of course I do.
当然有
-Shall we? -Yes.
-走吧？ -好
Shoko will make it in time.
硝子会及时赶到的
Yes.
是
ISHIKAWA PREFECTURE
（石川县）
ASUNARO REFORM
（翌桧装修工程）
I think you knew it was fraud.
你早就知道这是诈骗吧？
No comment.
我没什么好说的
-Sorry. -Hey, be careful!
-对不起 -小心一点
Um…
那个…
Your son got into medical school, right?
你儿子考上医学系了吧？
I saw it on social media.
我在社交网站上看到的
So?
所以呢？
I understand that
你有你的苦衷
you have your reasons and things you want to protect.
有想要守护的东西 这我可以理解
But the people who bought the apartment…
但是付钱买下公寓的人
Thank you very much.
谢谢光临
…also have their reasons…
也一样有自己的苦衷
Special sale!
特价促销
…and lives they want to protect.
有想要守护的生活
If this case is ruled as fraud in the civil trial,
如果民事法庭判定这是诈骗
it will eventually become a criminal case.
之后也会升级为刑事案件
If that happens, you will be punished.
这样的话 你也会受到刑罚
What?
什么？
If there's something you want to protect, please help us.
如果你有想要守护的东西 请你帮帮我们
Don't you think your actions here will affect you and your son's future?
你和你儿子的未来 就取决于现在的决定了
I don't know anything.
我什么也不知道
Please! I'm begging you.
拜托 我求求您
Please!
拜托您
Oh, Yoshio.
佳男
Starting this April, I've been appointed presiding judge.
四月开始 我就要被任命为部总理法官了
-Is that so. -Yup.
-这样啊 -对
That fraud case.
那起诈骗案
I'll be taking over from today.
从今天这个期日开始由我接手
The predecessor suddenly had to retire.
前任法官突然得要退休了
I'm proceeding with your firm transfer.
你转换事务所的事 我正在安排
Dad--
爸爸…
Once you meet them, you'll change your mind.
只要跟对方见了面 你一定会改变心意的
I'm looking forward to seeing you work.
我很期待你活跃的表现
-Good afternoon.
-您辛苦了 -辛苦了
I made a reservation in Akasaka. That's better for you, right?
我预订了赤坂的这家餐厅 赤坂的比较好吧
Did you prefer Ginza?
还是你们比较喜欢去银座？
You're just gonna get drunk anyway.
反正不管去哪里 都会喝醉吧
The apartment was fully occupied at the time of purchase.
买下公寓的当时 里面都住满了人
However, the fact that…
可是半年不到…
um… all the tenants had moved out within the next six months
房客就全部都退租了
is clearly a sign that a fraudulent act had taken place.
我方认为这明显是假造的行为
The tenants moving out was due to their own personal reasons
所有的房客会退租 都是因为个人的因素
and we believe it's difficult to hold the company responsible.
我方认为这很难说是公司的责任
Regarding the argument about disguising it as fully occupied,
另外 关于假造住户全满的说法
there is no clear evidence that the defendants, as brokers, were involved
没有明确证据显示 被告的中介业者有牵涉其中
and we believe it is a groundless claim.
我方认为这是毫无根据的主张
Plaintiff's counsel, do you have anything to say to that?
原告代理律师 对于刚刚的观点 你有什么要陈述的吗？
Yes. Um, let me see.
是 这个嘛
C-Could you repeat that again please?
可以请你再说一次吗？
Um, therefore we believe--
那个…因此我方认为…
Enough already!
够了
Your Honor. It's pointless to continue this.
审判长 再这样下去根本没有意义
What do you think a courtroom is?
你到底把法庭当成什么了？
I'm sure that as a tiny, tiny firm,
你们这种小之又小的事务所
you have your reasons like a lack of experience in court.
或许有缺乏法庭经验的苦衷
But we'd like you to come a little bit more prepared.
不过还是应该要 多做一点准备再来比较好
My apologies, Mr. Inuzuka.
非常抱歉 犬冢律师
By our next trial, we will come prepared so as not to cause you any inconvenience.
下次开庭之前 我们会好好准备 不会再给您添麻烦的
Your Honor.
审判长
-Yes. -I have plans. May we?
-是 -我接下来还有行程
I see.
也是
Is that alright?
可以吧？
-No… -The court is adjourned.
-不… -今天就此休庭
Good work everyone.
辛苦了
Anything?
怎么样了？
I can't reach her.
完全联络不上她
I wonder what happened.
到底怎么了？
Oh, she's calling.
她打来了
The president of the renovation company recorded the meeting with Mr. Tone.
装修公司的社长 在和刀根先生开会时有录音
And when I was heading back with that voice recorder…
在我带着录音笔要赶回来的路上…
Huh? What?
嗯？怎么了？
Hey! What's going on?!
喂！怎么回事？
No!
不要
The police are investigating it, but…
我请警方调查了 可是…
Are you really okay?
你真的没事吗？
I'm sorry. The evidence…
对不起 证据…
That doesn't matter.
那不重要
You're lucky you got away with a minor injury.
还好你只受了一点小伤
Why didn't you just let go?
为什么不马上放手呢？
I couldn't. It was an important piece of evidence!
不行 那是很重要的证据
You're more important to me, Shoko.
对我来说 你比较重要 硝子
Unforgivable.
不可原谅
I don't think a lawyer would do this.
我想律师应该不会做这种事
It's only a hunch, but…
这只是我的直觉…
When I went to see the president, someone was watching me.
我去找社长时 好像有人在监视我
I don't know if it's him who attacked me though.
袭击我的人是不是他我就不确定了
-Anyone in here? -No, it's not them.
-有在里面吗？ -没有 不是他们
-It's not them. -Not in here?
-不是 -这张也没有吗？
-No. -Anyone in this one?
-没有 -这张有没有看过谁？
Oh, it's him!
就是这个人
This man.
就是他…
Oh, I've seen him in that bar.
我也在酒吧里见过他
He's Mr. Mikogami's secretary.
他是御子神先生的贴身助理
So, Mikogami had him do it?
这么说是御子神指使他的？
Give me 24 hours.
请给我24小时
I'll memorize everything about him.
我会把这家伙的事情都记下来
Welcome back, sir.
欢迎回来
Mr. Mikogami, I've been watching your videos.
御子神先生 我一直有在看你的视频
Thank you.
谢谢
You smoke cigarettes?
你抽烟了吗？
Please keep it a secret.
请帮我保密
I often get questioned like that in smoking areas.
我在吸烟室也常被问 有点麻烦
I knew we could find you here.
我想来这里应该可以见到你
Four years ago, on November 8th, you posted
四年前的11月8日 你在照片墙上发文说
"Living in a hotel. No point renting a room." on your Instagram.
“我住在某间饭店 租房子完全没有好处”
And two months ago on January 15th, "I've lived in a hotel for four years now."
两个月前的1月15日 你也发文说 “我住在酒店里已经四年了”
I identified this hotel from the background of your online videos
你都是在房间里做线上沙龙的直播
that you always stream from your room.
我从视频背景找出是这家饭店的房间
You're scaring me.
你吓死我了
Let me get to the point.
我就开门见山了
We think that you are deeply involved in a real estate investment fraud case.
我们怀疑你卷入了不动产投资诈骗案
I'm Haneoka, the plaintiff's counsel.
我是原告代理律师羽根冈
I'm Ishida, a paralegal.
我是律师助理石田
I'm not following.
你们在说什么？
Didn't you get someone to attack her and steal the evidence?
不是你派人袭击她 把证据抢走的吗？
I'm not following.
你们在说什么？
We will prove your crime no matter what.
我们一定会证明你做的坏事
The number of laws keeps increasing because of people like you,
就是有你这样钻法律漏洞的人
who try to go through loopholes in the law.
法律条文才会越来越多
The law changes every year to crack them down,
为了取缔这些坏人 每年都要进行修法
but there are those like you, who still get away.
然而还是有你这样的人钻过漏洞
It's a cat-and-mouse game.
根本是猫捉老鼠
I don't know what this is about, but do you know who created the law?
我听不懂你们在说什么 不过你们知道法律是谁制订的吗？
-Who? -It's the powerful people.
-谁？ -强大的人
People with great power and influence.
有权力 有影响力 有这些强大力量的人
These are rules they created to make the world a better place.
法律是他们制订出来 想让世界变得更好的规则
However…
但是…
Because of that, it's designed for them to never lose no matter what happens.
就因为是强者制订的 不管怎样强者都不会输
Take casinos for example.
去过赌场吗？
It's designed for the gambling house to win.
赌场也不会让庄家输的 这是同样的道理
The law is not designed for the weak to win either.
制定法律也不是为了让弱者赢
Maybe this topic is a little difficult for local lawyers.
对你们这些小事务所律师来说 好像有点太难懂了
Oh, you're not even a lawyer yet.
对了 你连律师都不是 抱歉
Could you please testify in court about the contents of the voice recorder?
关于录音笔的内容 可以请您出庭作证吗？
I told you that I'm not talking!
就说了 我不会出面的
They got to him first.
他们已经找过他了吧
Geez…
可恶…
I'm off.
我出门了
What should we buy today?
今天要买什么？
I need to pee.
我要尿尿
That's why I told you to go earlier.
所以刚刚才叫你要去上厕所啊
Hey, it's not green yet.
等一下 还不是绿灯
But…
可是…
You can't hold it in?
憋不住了吗？
No, I can't.
不行 憋不住了
AO
（苍）
Ao! It's green!
苍 就是绿色
It's red!
红灯
Report it to the police.
那你快去告诉警方
Yes, I'm on my way!
好 我在路上了
You think we can get him now?
这样就能让他被逮捕了吧
Yes. If he's the one who set the fire, he'll be investigated for fraud too.
如果他是纵火犯 应该也会接受投资诈骗的调查
I'll let the police know.
我这边也会联系警方
Thank you very much!
太感谢了
Well done!
好样的
SEVEN DAYS LATER PUBLIC PROSECUTOR'S OFFICE
（七天后 检察厅）
Come in.
进来
I'm sorry to barge in.
不好意思 突然跑来
This character in my name is "Ao."
我名字里的这个字是“苍”字
But I thought maybe Taku meant the color "Ao," so I asked him.
但我想阿拓指的应该是颜色 就去问了他
And I was right.
果然没错
He was talking about a blue that is very close to green.
那是很接近绿色的蓝色
So, the lighter was green and not blue?!
所以打火机不是蓝色 而是绿色？
And I remembered someone who owned a green lighter.
我想起某个人有绿色打火机
Mr. Tone, please take a seat.
刀根先生 请坐
Did you set Mr. Hyuga on fire?
是你对日向先生纵火的 不是吗？
I didn't. I've already told you many times.
不是 我已经说多少次了
What's your shoe size?
你的鞋子尺寸是多少？
Huh?
什么？
How many centimeters?
多少公分？
You have leather shoes from a brand called Consensus, right?
你有Consensus 这个牌子的皮鞋吧？
Do you?
有吗？
I do. And?
有又怎样？
Footprints were collected from the crime scene.
从犯罪现场采集到的鞋印
They were the same size as your shoe--
跟你穿的鞋子是同样尺寸…
So what?
那又怎样？
Does that prove that it was me?
这样就能证明是我吗？
That's the problem.
问题就出在这里
These shoes are sold publicly,
因为是一般市面上买得到的鞋子
so that alone doesn't prove that you were at the park that day.
光是这样无法证明那天你人在公园里
Now, let me ask you about the lighter that was left at the crime scene.
那我们就来谈谈 现场遗留下来的打火机吧
You're a smoker, right? Do you use a lighter?
你抽烟吧？会用打火机吗？
I do. So what?
有又怎样？
Wasn't it your lighter that was left at the scene?
现场遗留下来的打火机不是你的吗？
That's the reason you're suspicious of me?
你这样怀疑我 有什么根据吗？
You're treating me like a criminal just because I smoke?
只因为我抽烟就把我当犯人吗？
You know, this isn't a deciding factor either.
这也缺乏决定性的要素啊
That lighter's color and shape are also common.
毕竟那个打火机的颜色和形状很常见
But I won't give up.
但我不会放弃的
I find you suspicious. I will prove that the lighter--
我觉得你很可疑 一定会证明那是你的打火机…
It's the same as those shoes you mentioned.
跟刚刚提到的鞋子一样啦
There are tons of green lighters out there.
绿色的打火机到处都有
What?
啊？
Did I mention that the lighter was green?
我提过打火机是绿色的吗？
The eyewitness testified that
目击者的证词里提到
another person started the fire with a green lighter.
有另一个人用绿色打火机纵火
But it's burnt black.
但它们都烧得焦黑了
You knew it was green because you did it.
会知道那个打火机是绿色的 是因为你就是犯人吧
No! It was a guess.
不是 我只是随口乱说的
You own a green lighter. Correct?
你有绿色的打火机吧？
A booby prize for your company's golf competition
公司高尔夫球比赛的吊车尾奖品
and the only one in the world.
全世界只有这一个
You will be prosecuted.
你会遭到起诉的
In that trial, we'll of course uncover the cause of this case,
当然在审判过程中 这个案子的背景
the real estate investment fraud case.
也就是不动产投资诈骗案 也会查个水落石出
Can't you imagine that confessing to everything now
趁现在全盘托出 表现出反省之意
and showing remorse will have a huge impact on your judgment?
对以后的量刑会有多大影响 你应该想象得到吧？
These are the complaints that Mr. Hyuga
日向先生多次利用家里的个人电脑
repeatedly sent from your home PC to Green Estate.
给绿色不动产发投诉信
The last one was sent the day before he passed away.
最后一封是在他过世前一天发出的
"President Oba, I can't do this anymore."
“大庭社长 我已经受够了
"If the law can't punish you, I'll have to do it myself."
既然法律无法制裁你们 那我只能自己动手了
"I'll show you something shocking tomorrow."
明天让你看个厉害的东西”
Tone thought this "something shocking" was evidence
刀根怀疑这个“厉害的东西” 会不会是某种证据
and he followed Mr. Hyuga that day.
所以在那天尾随日向先生
He watched, hoping that Mr. Hyuga would end his own life.
刀根原本袖手旁观 盼着日向先生会自焚
But when Mr. Hyuga failed to do so,
但日向先生没有那样做
he set him on fire.
于是他把他点着了
Tone is also starting to confess
刀根也开始坦承
who came up with the real estate investment fraud.
不动产投资诈骗是谁策划的
SECOND ORAL PROCEEDINGS
（第二次口头答辩）
"This real estate investment fraud
“此不动产投资诈骗
was planned entirely by Mr. Kyo Mikogami
全部都是御子神庆策划的
and both mine and Mr. Sakakibara's companies were only following orders."
我的公司和榊原社长的公司 只是听从指示而已
"Mr. Mikogami told me not to worry as no evidence will be found,
御子神先生花言巧语 ‘不会有证据的 别担心’
which is how I ended up taking part in fraudulent activities."
说服我参与了诈骗行动”
That was Mr. Tone's testimony we obtained
以上是在被告代理律师同意下
with permission from the defendant's representative.
从刀根先生那里取得的证词
Defendant's counsel, your response?
请被告方进行答辩
Oh…
哦…
Right.
这个嘛
Basically, I think
我方基本上
we would like to acknowledge the plaintiff's claim.
同意接受原告的请求
Your Honor. May I?
审判长 我可以发言吗？
I'll allow you to speak.
请说
Thank you very much for your advice the other day.
非常感谢您之前的建议
As you said, our tiny, tiny firm
如您所说 我们这小之又小的事务所
worked very hard to prepare and we were able to win.
拼尽全力准备 才能得到顺利的结果
I'd like to express my deepest gratitude.
真是感激不尽
The court is now adjourned.
今天在此休庭
Thank you very much!
谢谢您
I'm happy for you, Mr. Takaoka.
高冈先生 太好了
I'm glad I believed in you!
幸好我相信您
Thank you for everything.
谢谢你们的帮忙
Likewise.
彼此彼此
I'm so glad I got to meet you.
律师 能遇见你真是太好了
I'm happy to hear that.
听你这么说很开心
-Thank you very much. -I'm happy for you.
-律师 谢谢您 -太好了
I'm so relieved.
这下总算能安心了
I can't thank you enough.
真是太感谢了
Ouch! Ow, ow.
哎哟！痛
Good job today.
辛苦了
Dad.
爸爸
I…
我…
I'm an unreliable lawyer.
是个不可靠的律师
As you have seen,
就像你看到的
I get agitated and I can't even put up a brave front.
我心里会动摇 无法表现出坚强的样子
I can't even utilize my memorizing ability on my own.
唯一的长处是记忆力 但光靠我自己也无法好好运用
You're right.
就是啊
You're not capable at all.
你一点也不优秀
Honestly, I couldn't bear to watch you in the previous trial.
老实说 上次开庭我真的看不下去
I'm sorry, but I can't refer you to that firm.
很遗憾 我不能帮你介绍事务所
It's my reputation on the line.
事关我的信誉
I won't help you from now on.
我之后不会再帮你了
Got it?
知道吗？
Yes!
是
I truly am sorry that I can't live up to your expectations.
无法响应爸爸的期待 我很抱歉
But you finally saw who I really am.
但您终于正视我真正的样子了
That makes me happy.
我很高兴
Hm. We have…
你和我的…
different ideals.
理想不一样啊
Well, I guess you have things you want to do.
不过你有自己想做的事吧
Right?
有吧？
Yes.
是
Do your best.
那就加油吧
Yes, sir.
好
You're always watching, huh?
怎么每次都被你看到？
I'm guessing they're almost done too.
那边也差不多要结束了吧
Mr. Mikogami?
御子神先生吗？
Yeah.
对
-Yes. -Mr. Mikogami.
-是 -御子神先生
Sure. Understood.
好 我知道了
Okay, I'll see you later.
好 那就晚点见
Why wasn't he arrested?
他为什么没有被逮捕？
Mikogami claimed that the facts are groundless.
御子神声称那些指控都毫无根据
That Tone blamed him in his testimony out of desperation.
刀根的供词只是想要拖他下水
But there must have been evidence.
可是一定有什么证据吧
They don't have anything left!
就是什么证据都没留下啊
-There you are. -Sorry to make you worry.
-他来了 -抱歉 让各位担心了
Instructions to Tone and Sakakibara were sent from burner accounts.
对刀根和榊原的指示 都是透过免洗账号
I'm safe.
安全下庄
Mr. Yonekura.
这位是米仓先生
They're sent through many people all over the world
即使想追源头 中间也经过国内外好几个人
so they can't trace it back to Mikogami.
怎样也查不到御子神身上
Let's go.
我们走吧
No way…
不可能…
The money seems to be laundered through
金钱也会通过海外公司
an offshore company, so they can't get to the bottom of it.
洗得干干净净 根本无法查到底
Man, this is good.
天啊 好喝
Excuse me, champagne please.
不好意思 请给我香槟
So, we have to give up?
难道就只能放弃了吗？
This is the limit of local lawyers, huh?
这就是小律所律师的极限吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Hi there.
大家好
We didn't--
今天没有叫外卖…
It's not that. Do you have time for a consultation?
不是这样的 现在能提供咨询吗？
That regular of mine wants you to hear her out.
听一下我的常客想要说什么
Ah, sure. Oh!
可以 啊！
-Go ahead. -Um, yeah.
-请吧 -好
However much we clean up, passersby keep littering.
无论扫得多干净 路人还是会乱丢垃圾
It's endless.
简直没完没了
That's awful.
真是辛苦了
Is she the one you keep whining about? The regular who talks a lot--
该不会她就是你抱怨的 话匣子一打开就停不下来…
You know, littering is a crime.
乱丢东西也是犯罪
Yes. So, I want to sue everyone who litters.
所以我想要告所有乱丢垃圾的人
Well, everyone might be a little…
要全部告是有点困难…
CHIGASAKI, YOKOHAMA, MEGURO, SHINJUKU, EBISU, SHIBUYA, MOTOMACHI
（茅崎、横滨、目黑、新宿 惠比寿、涩谷、横滨市中区）
Oh!
啊！
-You scared me. -Huh?
-你吓死我了 -怎么了？
Whoa! Why? What?
为什么？做什么？
-Okay! What is it? -Thank you.
-谢谢你
-Sure? -I saw the light.
-是吗？ -我看到光了
The light?
光？
This will take time though.
虽然要花一点时间
What is it?
你在说什么？
I see!
原来如此
Let's show them what local lawyers are made of.
就让他见识一下 小律所的律师有多难对付吧
Yes.
好
Huh? What's going on?
怎么回事？
Excuse me, sir.
那位先生
You just threw your cigarette away, right?
刚刚你丢了烟蒂吧？
Right? I'm arresting you on the spot for violation of the Waste Disposal Act.
对吧？这违反了废弃物处理法 我要以现行犯逮捕你
What? You're overreacting.
什么？太小题大做了吧
No, no. We'll talk at the police station. Okay?
不…到局里谈一谈吧？
Oh dear. You messed up, Mr. Mikogami.
天啊 你这下惨了 御子神先生
-Thank you for your cooperation. -Sure.
-谢谢两位的协助 -不会
You can't arrest me for this.
这样就要逮捕人 太奇怪了吧
We'll just warn you if it's once or twice, but you're a habitual offender.
如果只是一两次 还可以口头警告 但你是长期惯犯吧
We've been watching you for the past month.
过去一个月 我们一直在监视你
You littered 53 times and we collected every single one of them.
你乱丢烟蒂53次 我们全都回收了
A DNA test will prove that they belong to you.
DNA鉴定应该能证明 这些烟蒂都是你丢的
Even so…
那又怎样…
Cigarette littering is a very malicious crime, which could lead to fire.
乱丢烟蒂恐怕会引发火灾 是非常恶劣的犯罪行为
So, I pressed charges.
所以我就去报案了
And the police accepted it.
警方也受理了
Let's go.
到局里去吧
May I have a moment with him?
我可以跟他说一下话吗？
You said that the law is created
你之前说过
for the powerful people only.
法律是专为强者所制订的
I disagree.
我不这么认为
Many of the laws, which increase in number every year,
每年不断增修的法律
are created to empathize with the appeals of the weaker people.
几乎都是为了响应弱势民众的要求
It's a history of them speaking up.
是这些人为自己发声的历史
It's a necessary rule
弱者也好 强者也好
for the powerful and the weak to live equally in the same world.
法律是让所有人在同一个世界里 平等生活的必要规则
I believe that's what the law is created for.
我认为法律是为此而制订的
And?
所以呢？
Even so, weak people will always be weak.
即使如此 弱小的人永远都会那么弱小
What's wrong with being weak anyway?
弱小有什么不对吗？
Huh?
什么？
Most of those you call the weak probably don't want to be powerful.
大多数被你称为弱者的人 应该也没有想要变强吧
They are the kind of people who want to live their lives peacefully
他们只是不想给别人添麻烦 也不想惹麻烦
without bothering nor be bothered by others.
只想要平平静静地过自己的生活
And those people are the backbone of our society.
正是这些人支撑起这整个社会
As ones who practice law,
我们身为法律人
we will continue to stand by and fight for those who live earnestly.
今后也会跟认真生活的人 一起并肩作战
As local lawyers.
以小律所律师的身份
Fine.
好吧
You can fight all you want.
想要怎么作战随便你们
But I'll be released immediately for a crime like this.
不过这种没什么大不了的罪名 我马上就会被释放了
In the end, that's all you could do.
说到底 你们还是动不了我的
I wonder if that's true.
那可就难说了
The suspect arrested on the spot for suspicion of
违反废弃物处理法 而遭警方以现行犯逮捕的
violation of the Waste Disposal Act was Kyo Mikogami, an investor.
是以投资人身份活跃商场的 御子神庆嫌犯
Mikogami is denying some of the charges
御子神嫌犯否认了部分指控
saying it's not a big deal and he shouldn't be arrested for it.
声称这又没什么大不了的 不应该就这样逮捕人
Hello.
你好
MIKOGAMI WAS FIRED FROM CARBON NEUTRALITY BOARD
（御子神遭碳中和理事会除名）
I see. Okay.
这样啊 我知道了
HE'S FIRED. LOL
（御子神被开除了 笑死）
Stop the car. Stop it!
停车 快停下
I HEARD MIKOGAMI WAS DISMISSED. OH WELL.
（御子神被解除职务了 这也是没办法的事）
Damn it! It's only littering!
可恶 不就只是丢个烟蒂而已
MIKOGAMI IS SO LAME.
（御子神逊毙了）
I DIDN'T LIKE HIS COMMENTS ANYWAY.
（反正我原本就不喜欢他的发言）
ARRESTED FOR LITTERING. LOL
（因为丢烟蒂被抓 太好笑了）
Special fraud damage is increasing every year.
特殊诈骗的危害逐年增加
Their methods are getting more…
手法不断推陈出新…
The total damage of refund fraud in 2020 is more than 17 billion yen.
2020年的退款诈骗 被害总额超过了17亿日圆
Their methods are changing every year raising the total cost of damage.
特殊诈骗手法每年都在改变 被害总额也不断增加
Thank you very much. You have a case?
谢谢来电 请问是要委托吗？
Yes. I saw the news on investment fraud
对 我看到不动产诈骗的新闻
and I thought maybe we're being scammed too.
想着自己是不是也被骗了 所以才打电话
Right.
好
You need consultation?
您要咨询什么事？
I want to press charges against my last workplace.
我也想告发之前的职场
You want to press charges. Just a moment please.
告发是吗？请稍等一下
Haneo, she's pressing charge!
羽男先生 她那是告发
What is this, a ramen shop?
这里又不是拉面店
I'll make the tea.
茶我来泡就好
Thanks.
谢谢
Sure.
好
Oh, Shoko.
硝子
Yeah?
怎么了？
Life is shorter than you think.
人生苦短 短得出乎意料
There's no life without regrets.
人生不可能完全没有遗憾
But isn't it better to have less of it?
但能少一个算一个 不是吗？
Isn't Taku coming today?
阿拓今天不会来吗？
No. He doesn't like to go out.
对 他不喜欢出门
It's beautiful.
好美
It is.
对
You and Mr. Haneoka
石子学姐和羽根冈律师
cleared me and Taku of suspicion.
洗清了我和阿拓的嫌疑
I think that's what inspired him to write this.
他是怀抱着这样的心情 写下这幅字的吧
If the sky is always clear,
只要一直是晴天
we wouldn't need an umbrella.
就不用撑伞了
I missed the chance to say this.
有件事我忘记说了
Yes?
什么事？
I couldn't do it by myself after all.
我自己一个人果然不行
The last trial.
上次的审判
I felt that I wasn't a full-fledged lawyer or even a half-fledged one.
别说是个独当一面的律师了 感觉我连半个都算不上
But when you're with me,
但是 跟石子小姐在一起的话
it feels like I can be double-fledged or even more than that.
感觉就能发挥双份以上的实力
So…
所以…
Please continue to stay by my side.
请你以后继续陪在我身边
What? Eww!
什么？
No!
不
What's your problem?!
你有什么问题？
What is this?
什么情况？
I went out of my character to tell you that
我是说以伙伴和律师助理的身份
I'd like to have you by my side as a partner and a paralegal.
今后也请多多指教 难得说些平常不会说的话
But you ruined it. Forget it.
你那是什么反应 算了
I decline.
我拒绝
You decline?!
竟然拒绝？
Forget it.
算了
I…
我…
I've decided to take the bar exam.
决定去考司法考试
Seriously?
真的吗？
I felt that
我感觉
I want to be a lawyer and be of more help to the clients.
我想成为律师 这样就能帮委托人更多的忙
It's thanks to you.
这都多亏了你
Me?
我吗？
I think we can be so much more than double-fledged too.
我也觉得跟你联手 可以发挥两人份以上的力量
So…
所以…
I'll be by your side
我会以律师伙伴的身份
as your lawyer partner.
陪在你身边
But isn't the application period over?
但是今年不是已经截止报名了吗？
Oh.
嗯
Dad had applied for me.
爸爸已经帮我报名了
Oh, my.
我的天
I'm going to stop giving up
我已经不想要
on trying.
再自我放弃了
BAR EXAMINATION VENUE
（司法考试会场）
Please move away!
麻烦让一让
Are you alright?
没事吧？
Man, it's another hot day.
天哪 今天也好热
Summer in Japan is becoming crazy, huh?
日本的夏天也太热了吧？
Again?
又来了吗？
"Again"?
“又来了”？
You showed up with such perfect timing.
在绝妙的时间点突然现身
Oh, could it be that
你该不会
you were hiding behind the pillar waiting for me?
又一直躲在柱子后面 等到适当时机才出现吧？
You seem better than I thought.
你比我想得还要有精神
What pillar?
什么柱子？
Go and pass the exam.
快去考试吧
I'll be off.
我出发了
BAR EXAMINATION VENUE
（司法考试会场）
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰